JACKSON HOLIDAY WHEELER JAVASCRIPT DEVELOPER



github.com/jhwheeler



+359 899 980 475



🏠 Sofia, Bulgaria

I am a Javascript developer with a background in copywriting, linguistics, and psychology. Fascinated with the creative process that software development embodies, I love to build and observe the psychological interaction between user and product. My main goal as a developer is to create interactive, engaging, and effective products to help conscious entrepreneurs grow their businesses and reach wider audiences.

Throughout my life I have been blessed with the gift of travel, having journeyed to 65 countries on 6 continents. In awe of the wide variety of human languages I heard through my travels, I became enamored with the structure of syntax and morphology. This led me to the discovery of programming languages when I was 9 years old, whereupon I taught myself the fundamentals of C++ and Python.

My focus shifted to natural languages, leading me to choosing Classical Linguistics as my university speciality. Dedicated to mastering the art of language, I now speak 7: English, French, Bulgarian, Portuguese, Spanish, Italian, and German.

Over the past few years however, my love for syntax and structure took over, rekindling my interest in computer languages. Diving into the world of modern web development, I have spent the last year learning the art of Full Stack Javascript programming, and am now keen on expanding my skills by supporting a collaborative team with a modern, cutting-edge tech stack.



Systematic

Analytical

Creative

Team-Oriented

Optimistic

Honest

Open-minded

Innovative













Professionally

Personally

Free time



Javascript (ES6) React Node.js **Express**

MongoDB

HTML5 & CSS3

WordPress

Branding Color Theory Copywriting French, Bulgarian, Portuguese, Spanish

WORK EXPERIENCE

Web Developer: November 2016 - Present Mythica Creative

As a Web Developer at the web and brand design agency Mythica Creative, I've been in charge of taking high-fidelity wireframes, design concepts, and/or mockups and transforming them into interactive websites.

Responsibilities:

Build responsive, engaging websites and landing pages for our clients in their preferred tech stack
Act as main liaison with the client to determine their needs and desires regarding the current project
Build brand strategy, along with our Art Director, for clients undergoing (re)branding, which has been the case
with most clients

Head Writer: October 2014 - January 2017 Mythica Creative

As the Head Writer of Mythica Creative, I was honoured to help conscious entrepreneurs reach greater audiences and manifest their mission.

Responsibilities:

Write engaging copy for web and print media, mostly web sites, landing pages, and sales brochures
Act as main liaison with the client to determine their needs and desires regarding the current project
Build brand strategy, along with our Art Director, for clients undergoing (re)branding, which has been the case
with most clients

Harmony Analyst and Consultant: March 2013 - October 2014 Life Design Enterprises, Inc.

After having completed my Harmony Analyst and Consultant Training, I joined the education team full-time to help others learn more about themselves and their path in life. Coaching people all around the world with the simple, yet powerful tools of the Harmony System, I learned an incredible amount about psychology, education, and the creative process.

Responsibilities:

Analyze clients' personalities based on the tested principles of the Harmony System Coach clients to use this newfound knowledge to improve their lives in practical and meaningful ways Write content for Harmony System courses and programmes

Private English Tutor: September 2012 - January 2014

Tutoring a variety of people from all walks of life, I led my students to greatly improve their English skills. I focused on professionals with an intermediate level of English, guiding them to reach the advanced level necessary to compete in the global market.

Responsibilities:

Hold private and group classes with a wide range of students Create lesson plans that engage the students and promote interactive learning

EDUCATION

Thinkful Fullstack Web Development Bootcamp January - June 2017

At Thinkful, the #1 rated coding bootcamp, I've learned how to create fullstack web apps and sites with Node.js, React, Express, and MongoDB. During the course, students get the opportunity to build four web apps to apply and exercise their knowledge.

University of Sofia 2011 - 2015

Classical Philology and Linguistics entails learning Latin, Ancient Greek, and Sanskrit, along with the literature, philosophy, and history of these great cultures. This education gave me a deep understanding of our cultural heritage, as well as the intricacies of syntax, morphology, and semantics.

Carlucci American International School of Lisbon 2009 - 2010

CAISL is one of the premier international preparatory schools in Europe. The curriculum is broad, giving students the skills to live and work in an increasingly global market. I highly appreciated the opportunity to live and study with such a large variety of students from all over the world, all of us privileged to received the education of a lifetime.

School Year Abroad in Rennes, France 2008 - 2009

School Year Abroad, founded in 1964, is an incredible homestay study programme where students have the opportunity and the privilege to live for one year in full immersion in the country of their choice. Living with a host family and having all classes in the local language — in my case, French — I and my colleagues developed our cultural awareness and communication skills to a high level.

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

English Teacher Manikhinna Buddhist Monastery, Sri Lanka Pisco Elqui Elementary School, Chile August 2010 to June 2011

Teaching English at the Manikhinna Buddhist Monastery in Sri Lanka and Pisco Elqui Elemntary School in Chile was an incredible experience. As a full-time volunteer, I had the opportunity to help young monks and village children advance their understanding of the English language. They were all highly motivated to learn, and their enthusiasm was truly inspiring, preparing them to connect with the greater world on a much deeper level.